<ThemeEntityData xmlns:i="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://schemas.datacontract.org/2004/07/WSU.Locations.DTO"><AttributeValues><AttributeValuesData><AttributeName>Bark</AttributeName><AttributeType>Text</AttributeType><AttributeValue>Dark gray to brown, becoming platy on old trunks, resembles bark of apple trees. </AttributeValue><EntitiyId>290</EntitiyId></AttributeValuesData><AttributeValuesData><AttributeName>Common Name</AttributeName><AttributeType>Text</AttributeType><AttributeValue>Red Horsechestnut</AttributeValue><EntitiyId>290</EntitiyId></AttributeValuesData><AttributeValuesData><AttributeName>Cultivars</AttributeName><AttributeType>Text</AttributeType><AttributeValue>Fort McNair red horse-chestnut (Aesculus x carnea 'Fort McNair'):  30 feet high and wide with a rounded form.  Some resistance to leaf blotch.  Pink flowers with yellow throats.


Ruby horse-chestnut (Aesculus x carnea 'Briotii'):  25 to 30 feet high with the same spread, this cultivar has dark rosy red flowers with yellow throats.  The leaves have a red mid-rib.
</AttributeValue><EntitiyId>290</EntitiyId></AttributeValuesData><AttributeValuesData><AttributeName>Description</AttributeName><AttributeType>Text</AttributeType><AttributeValue>This hybrid of Aesculus hippocastanum and Aesculus pavia has very large, dark green leaves composed of five to seven leaflets, and will ultimately reach a height and spread of 30 to 40 feet (Fig. 1). Although deciduous, Red Horsechestnut does not produce any appreciable fall color and is well-suited for use as a specimen. The tree is quite striking with dark green, coarse-textured foliage. Pyramidal in shape when very young, Red Horsechestnut develops slowly into a round, very dense shade tree by five to seven years of age, and is outstanding in the landscape for its beautiful springtime display of blossoms. The multitude of pink to bright scarlet blooms appear onderect, eight-inch-long panicles at each branch tip and are quite attractive to bees and hummingbirds. The prickly, rather messy, poisonous seedpods appear in fall.
</AttributeValue><EntitiyId>290</EntitiyId></AttributeValuesData><AttributeValuesData><AttributeName>Flower</AttributeName><AttributeType>Text</AttributeType><AttributeValue>Flowers are rose-red born on a 6-8" cone-shaped terminal cluster individual flowers are 1-1 1/2 " long and slightly prickly. 
</AttributeValue><EntitiyId>290</EntitiyId></AttributeValuesData><AttributeValuesData><AttributeName>Fruit</AttributeName><AttributeType>Text</AttributeType><AttributeValue>Nearly round with thick, leathery somewhat spiny husks enclosing 1 to 3 smooth, chestnut brown seeds; ripening in the fall
</AttributeValue><EntitiyId>290</EntitiyId></AttributeValuesData><AttributeValuesData><AttributeName>Hardiness Zone</AttributeName><AttributeType>Text</AttributeType><AttributeValue>5-7</AttributeValue><EntitiyId>290</EntitiyId></AttributeValuesData><AttributeValuesData><AttributeName>Height</AttributeName><AttributeType>Text</AttributeType><AttributeValue>30-40'</AttributeValue><EntitiyId>290</EntitiyId></AttributeValuesData><AttributeValuesData><AttributeName>Leaf</AttributeName><AttributeType>Text</AttributeType><AttributeValue>Opposite, palmately compound with usually only 5 leaflets, leaflets are obovate, 3-6" long, doubly serate leaf margins, top is lustrous dark green and bottom is nearly glabrous, petiole 2 1/2-4"long
</AttributeValue><EntitiyId>290</EntitiyId></AttributeValuesData><AttributeValuesData><AttributeName>Minnesota Native</AttributeName><AttributeType>Boolean</AttributeType><AttributeValue>0</AttributeValue><EntitiyId>290</EntitiyId></AttributeValuesData><AttributeValuesData><AttributeName>Outstanding Features</AttributeName><AttributeType>Text</AttributeType><AttributeValue>Splendidly rounded tree with large beautiful rose-red flower clusters that bloom in the spring. 
</AttributeValue><EntitiyId>290</EntitiyId></AttributeValuesData><AttributeValuesData><AttributeName>Scientific Name</AttributeName><AttributeType>Text</AttributeType><AttributeValue>Aesculus x carnea
</AttributeValue><EntitiyId>290</EntitiyId></AttributeValuesData><AttributeValuesData><AttributeName>Sun Exposure</AttributeName><AttributeType>Text</AttributeType><AttributeValue>Full sun</AttributeValue><EntitiyId>290</EntitiyId></AttributeValuesData><AttributeValuesData><AttributeName>Width</AttributeName><AttributeType>Text</AttributeType><AttributeValue>30-40'</AttributeValue><EntitiyId>290</EntitiyId></AttributeValuesData></AttributeValues><DefaultImagePath/><Description>This hybrid of Aesculus hippocastanum and Aesculus pavia has very large, dark green leaves composed of five to seven leaflets, and will ultimately reach a height and spread of 30 to 40 feet. Although deciduous, Red Horsechestnut does not produce any appreciable fall color and is well-suited for use as a specimen. The tree is quite striking with dark green, coarse-textured foliage. Pyramidal in shape when very young, Red Horsechestnut develops slowly into a round, very dense shade tree by five to seven years of age, and is outstanding in the landscape for its beautiful springtime display of blossoms. The multitude of pink to bright scarlet blooms appear on direct, eight-inch-long panicles at each branch tip and are quite attractive to bees and hummingbirds. The prickly, rather messy, poisonous seedpods appear in fall.</Description><DisplayName>Red Horsechestnut</DisplayName><EntityId>290</EntityId><GeoLocation/><Locations/><Resources/></ThemeEntityData>