<ThemeEntityData xmlns:i="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://schemas.datacontract.org/2004/07/WSU.Locations.DTO"><AttributeValues><AttributeValuesData><AttributeName>Common Name</AttributeName><AttributeType>Text</AttributeType><AttributeValue>Black Walnut</AttributeValue><EntitiyId>166</EntitiyId></AttributeValuesData><AttributeValuesData><AttributeName>Bark</AttributeName><AttributeType>Text</AttributeType><AttributeValue>Dark brown to grayish black, divided, deep, narrow furrows into thin ridges, forming a roughly diamond shaped pattern.</AttributeValue><EntitiyId>166</EntitiyId></AttributeValuesData><AttributeValuesData><AttributeName>Description</AttributeName><AttributeType>Text</AttributeType><AttributeValue>The Black Walnut is known for yielding very fine wood that's been used for cabinets and other furniture pieces. Overharvesting of trees for the wood has greatly reduced the native populations in the wild. Native Americans used the nuts for food and boiled the tree sap for syrup. They also reportedly threw the husks into ponds to poison fish, making them easier to catch. These trees give off chemicals that prevent many other plants from growing in their vicinity, thereby giving themselves the competitive advantage for nutrients and light. The fruit husks are very difficult to open and they're sticky and will stain hands. The ball-shaped fruits often litter the ground and the husk gradually decays to expose the dark, rough shelled nut. Juglans is the classical Latin name for the European walnut, from Jovis, of Jove or Jupiter, and glans, nut.</AttributeValue><EntitiyId>166</EntitiyId></AttributeValuesData><AttributeValuesData><AttributeName>Flower</AttributeName><AttributeType>Text</AttributeType><AttributeValue>Dark brown to grayish black, divided, deep, narrow furrows into thin ridges, forming a roughly diamond shaped pattern.</AttributeValue><EntitiyId>166</EntitiyId></AttributeValuesData><AttributeValuesData><AttributeName>Fruit</AttributeName><AttributeType>Text</AttributeType><AttributeValue>1 1/2-2 1/2" wide, spherical, husk-covered nut, sometimes in pairs or 3s. Husk very thick, light green, surface roughly dotted with no seams or ridges. Nut has irregularly ridged, dark brown, very thick shell. Contains edible seed.</AttributeValue><EntitiyId>166</EntitiyId></AttributeValuesData><AttributeValuesData><AttributeName>Hardiness Zone</AttributeName><AttributeType>Text</AttributeType><AttributeValue>4-9</AttributeValue><EntitiyId>166</EntitiyId></AttributeValuesData><AttributeValuesData><AttributeName>Height</AttributeName><AttributeType>Text</AttributeType><AttributeValue>70-90'</AttributeValue><EntitiyId>166</EntitiyId></AttributeValuesData><AttributeValuesData><AttributeName>Leaf</AttributeName><AttributeType>Text</AttributeType><AttributeValue>Alternate, pinnately compound, 12-24" long, 15-23 leaflets, often missing the terminal leaflet. Each leaflet 2-5"long, 3/4-2" wide, ovate-oblong to ovate-lanceolate, leaves fragrant when crushed</AttributeValue><EntitiyId>166</EntitiyId></AttributeValuesData><AttributeValuesData><AttributeName>Minnesota Native</AttributeName><AttributeType>Boolean</AttributeType><AttributeValue>1</AttributeValue><EntitiyId>166</EntitiyId></AttributeValuesData><AttributeValuesData><AttributeName>Scientific Name</AttributeName><AttributeType>Text</AttributeType><AttributeValue>Juglans nigra</AttributeValue><EntitiyId>166</EntitiyId></AttributeValuesData></AttributeValues><DefaultImagePath/><Description>The Black Walnut is known for yielding very fine wood that's been used for cabinets and other furniture pieces. Overharvesting of trees for the wood has greatly reduced the native populations in the wild. Native Americans used the nuts for food and boiled the tree sap for syrup. They also reportedly threw the husks into ponds to poison fish, making them easier to catch. These trees give off chemicals that prevent many other plants from growing in their vicinity, thereby giving themselves the competitive advantage for nutrients and light. The fruit husks are very difficult to open and they're sticky and will stain hands. The ball-shaped fruits often litter the ground and the husk gradually decays to expose the dark, rough shelled nut.  Juglans is the classical Latin name for the European walnut, from Jovis, of Jove or Jupiter, and glans, nut.</Description><DisplayName>Black Walnut</DisplayName><EntityId>166</EntityId><GeoLocation>[{"Lat":"44.046150","Lng":"-91.642670"}]</GeoLocation><Locations><LocationData><EntityId>166</EntityId><EntityName>Black Walnut</EntityName><EntityType>Tree</EntityType><GeoLocation>[{"Lat":"44.046150","Lng":"-91.642670"}]</GeoLocation><IsDefaultLocation>true</IsDefaultLocation><LocationId>438</LocationId></LocationData><LocationData><EntityId>166</EntityId><EntityName>Black Walnut</EntityName><EntityType>Tree</EntityType><GeoLocation>[{"Lat":"44.046160","Lng":"-91.642730"}]</GeoLocation><IsDefaultLocation>false</IsDefaultLocation><LocationId>439</LocationId></LocationData><LocationData><EntityId>166</EntityId><EntityName>Black Walnut</EntityName><EntityType>Tree</EntityType><GeoLocation>[{"Lat":"44.046140","Lng":"-91.642740"}]</GeoLocation><IsDefaultLocation>false</IsDefaultLocation><LocationId>440</LocationId></LocationData></Locations><Resources/></ThemeEntityData>